Oh, hey, you guys?
喔，嘿，你們大家
I couldn't get a reservation for the night of my birthday..
我生日當天晚上訂不到餐廳…
so we'll have to do dinner Thursday night.
所以我們要改到星期四晚上
- Thursday? But that's Halloween. - So?
-星期四？但是那是萬聖節耶！ -那又怎樣？
It's just spooky, that's all.
只不過是很詭異而已
So, is Mike coming to dinner?
那，麥克也會跟我們吃晚餐嗎？
No. It's my first birthday with a boyfriend, and he has to work.
不會，我第一次可以跟男朋友過生日 他卻要上班
I'd get mad at him, but I think it's too soon to show my true colors.
我很想對他發脾氣 但是我想這會太快露出馬腳
I would make the reservation for five. One of us has to stay with Emma.
那這樣我會只訂五個人的位子 我們其中一個要留下來照顧艾□
- Which one of us should go to dinner? - Rachel!
-我們該誰去晚餐呢？ -瑞秋！
Actually, I was thinking maybe both of us could go.
事實上，我想或許我們兩個都可以去
Oh. Yeah.
哦，真好！
Thanks. I'll put a lot of extra thought into your gift.
謝謝，我會多用點心準備你的禮物
All right, so great, we can all go now.
好了，太棒了，我們全部都可以去
That is fun! Hey! You know what?
真棒！嘿！你們知道嗎？
We all haven't been together, the six of us, in such a long time.
我們六個人已經很久沒有這樣在一起了
What are you talking about? We're together now.
你在說什麼呢？ 我們現在就在一起啊？
Mon? Chandler's not here.
摩妮卡，錢德並不在這裡
Oh, dear God.
喔，老天
The One With Phoebe's Birthday Dinner
本集播出：菲比的生日晚餐
rianystar壓制iPod-MP4
（土爾沙）
Hello. It's nice to see our team together for the first time.
大家好，很高興第一次我們全員到齊
Now, before we get started, are there any questions?
現在，在我們開始之前 有任何問題嗎？
- Yes. Ken, is it? - That's right.
-是的，肯，對吧？ -沒錯
Is it true the reason you're in Tulsa is, you fell asleep in a meeting..
聽說你會來土爾沙的原因 是因為你在開會的時候睡著…
and took the job without realizing what you were saying yes to?
然後隨口就答應接下 這份你根本搞不清楚的工作，是嗎？
Well, don't believe everything you hear, Ken.
嗯，別道聽塗說，肯
But yeah, that's true.
但是沒錯，那是真的
All right, let's get started by taking a look at last quarter's figures.
好了，我們先開始看一下上一季的數字
Claudia, aren't you supposed to blow smoke up the boss's ass?
克勞蒂亞，你不是應該要 先問一下老闆可不可以抽煙嗎？
- I'm sorry. Does the smoke bother you? - No. I smoked for years. Then I quit.
-我很抱歉，你介意我抽煙嗎？ -不，我抽了好多年，然後戒了
Right now, I can't remember why.
現在也忘了為什麼要戒
You're not allowed to smoke in this office, right?
在辦公室不准抽煙的，不是嗎？
Yes, in Oklahoma it's legal to smoke in offices with 15 people or less.
可以的，在奧克拉荷馬 在十五人以下的辦公室 抽煙是合法的
- Would you like one? - Would Joey like two pizzas?
-你要來一根嗎？ -喬伊想要吃兩個披薩嗎？
You don't know what I'm talking about.
你不知道我的意思嗎？
All right, look. I don't smoke anymore.
好了，聽著，我戒煙了
But if the rest of you want to light up, go ahead, it's fine.
如果你們其他人也想抽 請便，沒關係的
So, you all smoke, then?
原來你們全部都抽煙
You know, it's almost rude that I'm not smoking.
你們知道嗎？ 我不抽煙反而看起來很沒禮貌
- That's not true. If you don't want.. - Ken, please!
-沒那回事，如果你不想… -肯，拜託！
No, I can't. I can't smoke. If I smoke, my wife would kill me.
不，不行，我不能抽煙 如果我抽煙，我老婆會殺了我
I'm sorry, but isn't your wife back in New York?
不好意思，但是你老婆不是在紐約嗎？
I've always liked you, Ken.
我一直都很喜歡你，肯
Trick or treat.
不給糖就搗蛋
- Hey. - And "treat" it is.
-嘿 -真是好吃啊！
Wow. So glad I changed.
哇，幸好我有換衣服
I almost wore my threadbare robe that can't contain my breasts.
我差一點就穿上那件 連胸部都遮不住的破睡袍
This is not what I'm wearing. I'm ovulating..
我不是要穿這件出門 我正在排卵…
and Chandler's gonna be home. So, I thought we would try before dinner.
而錢德很快就回來了 所以我想我們可以在晚餐前試一下
Oh, I thought we'd all go over together.
喔，我以為我們全部要一起過去
All right, I'll just meet you there at dinner.
好了，我們晚餐見
Unless, I mean, if it helps, I could stay and watch.
除非，我是說，如果有幫助的話 我可以留下來當觀眾
- No! - Well, I didn't want to anyway.
-不必！ -喔，反正我也不想看
You know, just thought I'd be polite and offer.
你知道的，我只是想要 禮貌性地問一聲
Wait, does this mean you'll be late?
等一下，這表示你們會遲到嗎？
We haven't seen each other in over a week.
我們已經超過一個星期沒有見面了
We'll probably be the first ones there.
我們可能會是第一個到的
Okay. See you there. Happy humping.
好了，待會見，祝你們搞的愉快
Hey. Well, hey!
嘿！
Wow, somebody smoked out here?
哇，有人在這裡抽煙嗎？
My God, don't people know you're not allowed to smoke in public spaces?
天啊，難道他們不曉得 在公共場所是不可以抽煙的嗎？
Actually, in Oklahoma smoking's legal in offices with fewer than 15 people.
事實上，在奧克拉荷馬 在少於十五人的辦公室抽煙是合法的
Oh, you smoked.
喔，是你抽的！
No. I just happen to know a lot of trivia about smoking in different states.
不是，我只是剛好知道 不同州的抽煙規定
For example, in Hawaii, cigarettes are called lei-lana-lukus.
例如，在夏威夷 香煙叫做雷拉納路卡斯
- Oh, Chandler, you stink of cigarettes! - Do you think Monica will smell it?
-喔，錢德，你身上都是臭煙味！ -你想摩妮卡會聞得到嗎？
Are you kidding? That woman has the nose of a bloodhound.
你在開玩笑嗎？ 那女人的鼻子像狗一樣靈
And the breasts of a Greek goddess.
胸部像希臘女神一樣美
Phoebe?
菲比？
I'm gonna go.
我要走了
Okay. Something to cover the smell.
好了，有什麼可以掩蓋味道
Oven cleaner.
爐灶清潔劑
Unscented.
無添加香味
Welcome home.
歡迎回來
I've missed you.
我好想你
- You want to join me in the bedroom? - No, thanks, I'm good.
-想要跟我進房間嗎？ -不，謝了，不用
Okay. So you want to play it that way, do you?
好的，你想要這樣玩，是嗎？
Well, you know what, actually, I just got off a plane..
嗯，你知道嗎？事實上 我才剛下飛機…
so I'm feeling gross. I should take a shower.
覺得有點髒 我應該先洗個澡
- Come here, you don't need a shower. - All right, the truth is..
-過來，你不需要洗澡 -好的，事實上是…
I soiled myself during some turbulence.
我在亂流的時候弄髒了自己
What do I smell? I smell smoke.
什麼味道？我聞到煙味
Did you smoke?
你有抽煙嗎？
Yes. But I just had one.
有，但是只抽了一根
Two.
兩根
Two tiny cigarettes. Okay, five.
兩小根，好吧，五根
A pack. Two pack.. A carton.
一包，兩包…一條
Three big fat cartons in two days!
兩天抽三大條香煙！
But it's over. I've made a decision, I'm not gonna smoke anymore.
但是都結束了，我已經決定 再也不要抽煙了
Well, those are for you.
嗯，那是要送給你的
All right. Well, we'll just see you when you get here. Bye.
好的，嗯，到時候見，拜
Oh, that was my mom. She's stuck in terrible traffic.
喔，那是我媽，她遇到大塞車
That is now the third sign that I should not leave Emma.
這是第三個徵兆 告訴我不應該離開艾□
- What are the other two? - Well, the first one is, I don't want to.
-另外兩個徵兆是什麼呢？ -嗯，第一個是，我不想要
And second one, I'm not going.
第二個是，我不要去
I know this is the first time we're leaving the baby.
我知道這是我們第一次離開艾□
I know how hard it is for you. But..
我知道這對你很困難，但是…
But everything's gonna be fine. I mean, my mom is gonna be with her.
但是一切都會很好的 我是說，我媽會在這裡照顧她
- She's great with kids. - She is?
-她很會照顧小孩的 -真的嗎？
Yeah.
真的
What about Monica?
那摩妮卡呢？
You only hear Monica's side of that. Okay, that little fatso was a terror!
你都只聽她說的話 那個肥妹是個恐怖份子！
- I just don't think I can do it. - Know what? You can and you should.
-我只是不認為我辦得到 -你知道嗎？你應該、也辦得到
Really, it will be good for you.
真的，這對你是有幫助的
In fact, you know what?
事實上，你知道嗎？
Go ahead to the restaurant, and I will wait for my mom..
你先去餐廳，我留下來等我媽…
and then I'll meet you there. No, no, really, you should go. Go out.
然後我再過去找你們 真的，你應該過去，出去
Really, the world is your oyster. Kick up your heels. Paint the town red!
真的，這世界是你的 甩開高跟鞋，揮灑出自己的顏色！
- You need to learn some new slang. - I'm serious. Come on, you should go.
-你是該學些新的廣告詞 -我是說真的，走吧，你該走了
Here. No, just go.
來，去吧
- Well.. - No, no! You know what?
-那… -不，不！你知道嗎？
You're not getting back in there! The baby's fine. Now, scram!
你別想要進去！寶寶沒事的！ 現在快走吧！
Yeah, hit the bricks!
是啊，邁開步伐走吧！
Tell your story walking!
什麼都免驚，向前行！
I was just going to say that I left my keys.
我只是要說，我忘記帶鑰匙了
Holy moley, are we in a pickle now!
老天啊，這下我們慘了！
Where is everyone? They're 40 minutes late.
他們人呢？已經遲到四十分鐘了
- I know. - I'm starving.
-我知道 -我餓死了
I knew we were coming here tonight. I ate nothing all day.
我知道我們今晚要來這裡 所以我整天都沒有吃東西
What about me? I only had one lunch today.
那我怎麼說呢？我才吃一頓午餐而已
So, are we expecting the rest of our party shortly?
那麼，其他的貴賓很快就會到臨嗎？
Yes, they are expected presently. Yeah.
是的，我們衷心期盼他們的即將到臨 是啊
Their arrival is in the offing.
他們即將現身了
Right. We have a table for two available.
好的，我們也有兩人座的位置
- Perhaps you'd.. - No, they're coming.
-或許你們… -不用了，他們要來了
We're waiting right here.
我們就在這裡等
Joseph!
喬瑟夫！（喬伊全名）
One needn't worry. They shan't be long.
沒有「您」需要擔心 他們應該不會太「漫長」
It's just that we do have some large parties waiting.
我們有一些人在等著要用餐
Oh, one really does have a stick up one's ass, doesn't one?
喔！有「您」真的 需要這樣機機車車的嗎？
Why would you start smoking again? It's so bad for you.
你為什麼又開始抽煙？ 它對身體那麼不好
It's only been two days. That's not enough time to..
我才開始抽了兩天 沒那麼快就…
That's totally unrelated.
這跟那個一點關係都沒有
How can you smoke in this day and age? Have you not seen that ad?
什麼時代了怎麼還會抽煙呢？ 你沒有看過反煙廣告嗎？
Where the little kid walks through Grandpa? It's chilling!
那個小孩走穿過他爺爺那個廣告 真是嚇死人了！
I messed up. It was a meeting. Everybody was smoking.
我搞砸了，不過是一個會議 每個人都在抽煙啊！
So what? Don't you have any willpower?
那又如何？你難道沒有任何意志力嗎？
Willpower? I've watched home movies of you eating Ding Dongs..
意志力？ 我看過你在吃巧克力的家庭錄影帶…
without taking the tinfoil off!
…連包裝紙都來不及打開！
You said that was sexy!
你說那看起來很性感！
Okay, look, can we just drop this? I'm not gonna smoke again.
好了，好了，可不可以算了？ 我不會再抽煙了
That's right, because I forbid you to smoke again.
沒錯，因為我禁止你抽煙
You forbid me?
你禁止我？
I've flown a long way to see my loving wife.
我大老遠飛回來見我可愛的老婆
Is she here, by the way?
對了，她在嗎？
Chandler, don't joke with me. Okay? I'm very, very upset right now.
錢德，別開玩笑，好嗎？ 我現在非常非常地不高興
- Is this the most upset you could be? - I think so.
-現在是你最不高興的時候嗎？ -我想應該是的
Well, then I might as well..
那，我何不就…
do this.
這樣做
Not really sure what to do now.
不確定接下來要幹麼
I'll tell you what we're gonna do.
我告訴你我們要做什麼
We're already late for Phoebe's birthday dinner.
我們要去參加菲比的生日晚餐 我們已經遲到了
So you're going to put out that cigarette..
所以你要把香煙熄掉…
we're gonna put this fight on hold, and go have sex.
我們先暫停吵架 先上床再說
Fine. What?
好，什麼？
What, do you have cigarettes in your ears?
怎樣？你耳朵是塞了香煙嗎？
Sex! This is the last day I'm ovulating. If we don't do it..
上床！今天是我排卵的最後一天 如果我們不做…
we're gonna have to wait until next month!
我們就要等到下個月了！
You're serious?
你是認真的嗎？
- Oh, yeah! - All right, fine, I'll do it, but no talking!
-喔，是的！ -隨便，做就做，但我不跟你說話！
- And no cuddling. - And no kissing your neck.
-而且沒有抱抱 -而且不親吻你脖子
Oh, good! I hate it when you do that!
喔，很好！反正我也很討厭你那樣做！
And lots of kissing your neck!
那我要盡量親你的脖子！
Okay, well, the super's not home.
嗯，管理員不在家
But my mother's gonna be here, and she has the key.
但是我媽快到了，她有鑰匙
I can't wait that long. You have to do something. Knock that door down!
我等不了那麼久，你得想想辦法 把門撞倒吧！
I would, but I bruise like a peach.
我也想，但是我就跟桃子一樣容易撞傷
Besides, you know, everything's gonna be fine. The baby's sleeping.
而且，你知道一切都會沒事的 嬰兒在睡覺
- What if she jumps out of the bassinet? - Can't hold her head up, but jumped.
-萬一她跳出搖籃呢？ -根本連頭都抬不高，還想跳
Oh, my God! I left the water running!
喔，天啊！我水龍頭還開著！
You did not leave the water running. Please, pull yourself together, okay?
你沒有讓水龍頭開著 拜託，冷靜一點，好嗎？
- Well, did I leave the stove on? - You haven't cooked since 1996.
-那，我有把爐子開著嗎？ -1996年之後你就沒有煮過飯了
Is the window open? If the window's open a bird could fly in and..
窗戶有開著嗎？如果開著 鳥可能會飛進來然後…
My God, you know what? I think you're right.
天啊，你知道嗎？我想你說對了
- Listen. - What? What?
-聽 -什麼？什麼？
A pigeon. No. No, wait, no. An eagle flew in!
是鴿子，不，等等，不 是老鷹飛進去了！
Landed on the stove and caught fire!
飛到爐子上然後燒了起來了！
The baby, seeing this, jumps across the apartment to the mighty bird's aid.
嬰兒看到這一切 從公寓這邊跳過去幫助老鷹
The eagle, however, misconstrues this as an act of aggression..
而老鷹卻誤判認為 這是個攻擊的行動…
and grabs the baby in its talon.
用爪子捉住嬰兒
Meanwhile, the faucet fills the apartment with water.
就在這時候，水龍頭的水 充滿了整間公寓
Baby and bird, still ablaze, are locked in a death grip..
嬰兒跟老鷹還在激戰中 雙方被死亡的陷阱困住…
swirling around the whirlpool that fills the apartment!
在公寓內的漩渦裡旋轉著！
Boy, are you gonna be sorry if that's true.
天，如果這一切是真的你就死定了
- Hello. - Hi.
-哈囉 -嗨
It's been an hour.
已經一個小時了
The maitre d' asked if you'd reconsider switching to a smaller table.
經理要我問你們是否要考慮換到小桌子
Maybe we should just eat now.
或許我們應該先用餐
You can't order until the entire party's arrived. Restaurant policy.
在人還沒有到齊之前你們不能點餐 這是餐廳規定
Well, how about this? Another table leaves, right..
好，那如果說另一桌離開了…
but there's still some food left on their plates.
但是他們的餐盤裡還有食物…
Okay, what's the restaurant's policy about people eating that?
餐廳有規定不能吃那些食物嗎？
- It's frowned upon. - But it happens.
-那是很不合宜的 -但是還是會發生啊
- All right, I got to go to the bathroom. - You can't go.
-好了，我要去廁所 -你不能去
No, no, no. I can't hold this table on my own.
不，不，不 我沒有辦法自己保住這張桌子
If they ask me to move, I'll cave.
如果他們要我換位子，我會屈服的
Well, if you ask me to stay, I'll pee.
如果你要我留下來，我會尿褲子的
Good evening, miss.
晚安，小姐
Miss?
小姐？
Miss? Miss?
小姐？小姐？
Okay, fine, I'll move. All right. You don't have to manhandle me.
好了，算了，我換位子，好了 你不需要動手動腳的
- Where? - Okay.
-哪裡？ -好的
Thank you. Wow.
謝謝，哇
Will you stop staring at us now?
現在你可以停止盯著我們看了嗎？
That depends. Will your friend stop drinking olive oil directly from the bottle?
看情況，你朋友可以停止 喝那瓶橄欖油了嗎？
Probably not.
或許沒辦法
Finally. You guys made it.
終於，你們到了
Phoebe, who the hell..?
菲比，這些人是誰…？
What is taking you so long, Come on, let's get it over with!
你是在摸什麼摸這麼久 快點，我們早做早完成！
In a minute, sweet cakes.
馬上好，親愛的
Spend more time with the tie! That will make a baby.
多花點時間在領帶上！ 那樣可以生出小孩來
Look, I can't do this. I can't make love to you while we're fighting this way.
聽著，我做不到 我沒有辦法在吵架的時候還跟你做愛
Oh, sure. Now you're Mr. Sensitivity.
喔，是啊，現在你可真敏感纖細
But when you wanted to have sex after my uncle's funeral..
那當初你想在我叔叔喪禮之後做愛時…
That was a celebration of life!
那是慶祝生命！
All right, I'm not gonna do this.
好了，我不想這樣做
Is this the way you want our baby to be conceived?
你想要我們的孩子 在這種情況下受孕嗎？
No, you're right.
不，你是對的
We shouldn't do it like this.
我們不應該在這種情況下做
For what it's worth, I'm sorry.
反正，我很抱歉
I shouldn't have come down on you so hard about the smoking.
我不應該對你抽煙這件事這樣的刁難
So you had a few cigarettes. It's not the end of the world.
你是抽了幾根煙，又不代表世界末日
- Really? - Yeah.
-真的？ -是的
You are incredible.
你真不可思議
And listen, I'm not gonna smoke again.
聽著，我不會再抽煙了
And if I do, I promise I will hide it so much better from you.
如果我抽，我保證也會 隱藏到讓你看不出來
- Want to? - Let's celebrate life!
-想嗎？ -我們來慶祝生命！
Okay!
好了！
Oh, God.
喔，天啊
Oh, thank God you're okay.
喔，感謝上帝你沒事
I'm sorry we left. Mommy will never leave you again.
我很抱歉我們離開你 媽咪再也不會離開你了
Never, ever, ever again.
再也… 再也不會
Great. So let's get going.
太棒了，我們走吧
I mean it. After what just happened, I'm never leaving her again.
我是說真的，在經歷過剛剛的事之後 我再也不會離開她了
I understand. Separation is hard.
我瞭解，分離是很煎熬的
One time I was about to leave Ross to go to the beauty parlor.
有一次我要離開羅斯去美容院
And he got so upset he took off all his clothes..
他就變得很不開心 他把衣服脫光…
tucked his willy between his legs..
把小雞雞夾在雙腿間….
and cried out, "Mommy, I'm a girl. Take me with you."
然後哭喊「媽咪，我是女生 帶我跟你去」
Somehow, over time, it got easier to be apart from you.
物換星移之後 跟你分開已經變得容易很多了
You are welcome.
不客氣
- You know what? Let's not talk. - What?
-你知道嗎？我們還是不要說話 -什麼？
- I am still so mad at you for smoking! - But you said you forgave me.
-我對你抽煙的事還是很生氣！ -但你說你已經原諒我了
It was just a couple of cigarettes, no big deal.
只不過是幾根煙，沒有什麼大不了的
I was ovulating and you said you wouldn't have sex if we were fighting.
我正在排卵，而你卻說如果我們在吵架 你是不會跟我做愛的
- You tricked me to get me into bed? - That's right. I got mine.
-你騙我跟你上床？ -沒錯，我得到我想要的了
I feel so used.
我被利用了
Well, I guess they're not coming. You want to just order?
我想他們不會來了 你想要點了嗎？
Thank you.
謝謝
Waiter? All right, this is gonna go fast, so try to keep up.
侍者？好了，我會說很快 所以記好
Risotto with shaved truffles and the rib steak..
意大利扁面配松露切片 然後肋眼牛排…
with the golden chanterelles and the Bordelaise sauce..
加上酥炸雞油菇和波爾多紅酒醬…
unless any of that stuff I just said means "snails."
希望我以上說的那麼多東西 沒有包括「蝸牛」
It does not.
是沒有
Tomato tart, and which of the pastas would you recommend?
蕃茄餡餅，你建議哪種面呢？
- Oh, well they're both exquisite.. - Both it is. Thank you.
-嗯，兩種都很美味… -兩種都要，謝謝
Now, let's go, baby. It's food time. Bring it, bitch.
現在，快點，寶貝 用餐了，上菜吧，婊子
- Sorry about that. - It's quite all right.
-很抱歉 -沒關係
Oh, can I make a special request?
喔，我可以有個特殊要求嗎？
Can you bring everything as it's ready?
你可以全部一起上嗎？
- Appetizers, entrees, we don't care. - Hey!
-前菜，前餐，我們不介意 -嘿！
- I'll wait to put your order in. - What did I ever do to you?
-我可以等你們加點 -我有對不起你嗎？
Nothing, bitch.
沒有，婊子
You guys are over an hour late.
你們遲到一個多小時了
- What happened to you two? - So sorry.
-發生了什麼事？ -很抱歉
- We got locked out of the apartment. - That's a great story. Can I eat it?
-我們被鎖在公寓外面 -真是好借口，可以給我吃嗎？
And then Rachel wasn't sure she could leave the baby.
然後瑞秋在猶豫是不是要離開嬰兒
It wasn't easy, but it's your birthday and I did what I had to do.
不是很容易，但是今天是你生日 我做了我必須要做的事
And that's Judy over there at the bar with Emma?
那是茱蒂跟艾□在吧檯那邊嗎？
This is for the best. I'm not distracted, worrying about Emma..
這是最好的方式，這樣我才不會分心 擔心艾□…
how she's doing at home, and I'm gonna be completely here with you.
在家有沒有事 我得要完全跟你們待在這裡
- Oh, she spit up. She spit up. - What?
-喔，她吐了，她吐了 -什麼？
Judy? She spit.. Judy, look alive, Judy!
茱蒂？她吐… 茱蒂，醒醒，茱蒂！
- Thank you. - Thanks.
-謝謝 -謝謝
Oh, everything looks delicious.
喔，每道菜看起來都很美味
What should I have? What should I have?
我應該點什麼呢？ 我應該點什麼呢？
Never hit a woman. Never hit a woman.
不能打女人 不能打女人
I know what you mean, this menu's incredible.
我知道你的意思，菜單實在太棒了
Ross bruises like a peach. He bruises like a peach.
羅斯像桃子一樣容易受傷 他像桃子一樣容易受傷
Okay, I'll have the fig salad and the duck.
好了，我要點無花果沙拉 還有鴨肉
I'll have the soup and the salmon.
我要點湯跟鮭魚
Remember, whatever comes up first, okay?
記住，先做好的就先出，好嗎？
- Hurry.. - Happy birthday!
-快點… -生日快樂！
Son of a bitch!
狗娘養的！
- Where have you been? - Well, we had a little fight.
-你們去哪了？ -嗯，我們剛剛在吵架
I would never lie to get someone into bed.
我怎樣都不會騙人上床
You used to tell girls you were a Kennedy.
你曾經騙過女生你是甘尼迪家族的人
Thanks.
謝謝
Thanks. Wow.
謝謝，哇
A little tight, isn't it? Why didn't you get a bigger table?
有點擠，不是嗎？ 你為什麼不訂大一點的桌子呢？
You had a big table but they made you move.
你有訂，但他們要你換桌
Shut up, Monica.
閉嘴，摩妮卡
Oh, well, I suppose that Chandler will have the smoked duck.
嗯，我想錢德應該想要點「煙」熏鴨肉
And I suppose that Monica will have the manipulative shrew.
而我想摩妮卡應該想點酥「詐」鼠肉
How did I miss that?
我是怎麼沒看到那些呢？
- I'll give you another minute. - What, where you going?
-我再讓你們考慮一下 -什麼？你要去哪？
He said she wanted the shrew!
他說她想要鼠肉的！
Rach, come on, Emma's fine.
瑞秋，別這樣，艾□沒事的
You're turning into an obsessive mother, okay? You need to stop.
你已經變成過份關心的母親了 你要停止這樣
You ever hear the story about when Ross' mom went to the beauty salon?
你們有聽過羅斯他媽 去美容院的故事嗎？
- You mean the willy story? - They already know it.
-你是說小雞雞的事嗎？ -他們早就知道了
We've been waiting for you for a long time.
我們等你們好久了
- You should order. - That's okay.
-你們應該點餐了 -沒關係
- I told the waiter what they want. - Why would you do that?
-我告訴侍者他們要點什麼了 -你為什麼那樣做呢？
Chandler, control your woman.
錢德，控制一下你的女人
Okay, well.. Everybody has ordered.
好了，嗯… 既然大家都已經點餐了
I would like to start the celebration and make a toast to Phoebe.
我想要先敬菲比一杯 來開始今晚的慶祝
- She dropped her sock. - What?
-她襪子掉了 -什麼？
No. No, Emma dropped her sock.
-不，不，艾□的襪子掉了
- How do you know that? - She's over there.
-你怎麼知道？ -她就在那邊
- Mom's with her. - Mom's here?
-媽跟她在一起 -媽在這裡？
I wanted to have lunch with her today. She told me she was out of town.
我今天想跟她一起用午餐 她告訴我她不在附近
She still has not noticed that the baby's sock is on the ground.
她還是沒有注意到 嬰兒的襪子已經在地上了
It's a good toast.
真是敬的好
Look, will you please get her attention?
聽著，你可不可以叫她呢？
Mommy?
媽咪？
Mother.
媽
Oh, for God's sake, Judy, pick up the sock!
喔，天啊，茱蒂，把襪子撿起來！
Pick up the sock! Pick up the sock!
撿起襪子！撿起襪子！
I'm sorry, was that rude?
我很抱歉，這樣很沒禮貌嗎？
Did my little outburst..
我這樣的吼叫…
blunt the hideousness that is this evening?
有使今晚 變得比較難堪嗎？
Look, I know you have a lot going on..
聽著，我知道你們都有自己的事…
but all I wanted to do was have dinner with my friends on my birthday.
但我想要的只不過是跟我的朋友 一起吃晚餐慶祝我的生日
And you are all so late, and you didn't even have the courtesy to call.
你們全部都遲到 而且連打電話告知的禮貌都沒有
Well, it's too late now.
這已經來不及了
Phoebe, I don't think that's us.
菲比，我想那應該不是我們
Oh, well, this is.. This is not over! Hello?
喔，那，這個…還沒有完！ 哈囉？
I feel terrible. We should've been strong and left Emma at home.
真對不起她 我們應該堅強一點把艾□留在家
"We"?
我們？
There are some adult willy stories they don't know.
還有成人版的小雞雞事件他們沒聽過 -
We should've been stronger.
我們是該堅強點
- What is going on with you two? - Well, you see, I'm ovulating.
-你們倆是怎麼回事呢？ -喔，是這樣的，我正在排卵
Oh, yeah, that's what she says.
喔，是啊，她總是那樣說
Maybe you're not ovulating. Maybe it's a clever ruse to get me into bed.
或許你根本沒有在排卵 或許那只是要拐我上床的借口
Yeah, Smokey, that's what it was. I just can't get enough.
是啊，煙蟲，就是那樣沒錯 我就是很想要
You're not gonna believe this.
你們不會相信的
She tricked me into having sex with her.
她竟然騙我跟她上床
So? You got to have sex, right?
所以呢？你得要做愛的，不是嗎？
What's the matter with me? Why am I such a girl?
我是怎麼了？我又不是女生
- Okay. That was Mike. - Oh, Phoebe, honey, we are so sorry.
-好了，那是麥克 -喔，菲比，親愛的，我們很抱歉
You are totally right. We are here 100 percent..
你說的對極了 我們在這裡會全心全意…
and we love you, and we are ready to start your birthday celebration.
而且我們愛你 我們已經準備好要開始慶祝你的生日了
You guys, that means the world to me.
你們，這對我實在太意義重大了
Okay, I'm gonna take off.
好了，我要走了
What?
什麼？
I love you guys too, but, Mike got off work early.
我也愛你們，但是 麥克提早下班了
Wait.
等等
I'm not the.. I'm not the kind of girl that just ditches her friends..
我不是那種會拋下朋友…
to be with her boyfriend.
見色忘友的人
You know what? I am.
你們知道嗎？事實上我是…
Bye, guys. Judy! Bye.
再見，大家，茱蒂！再見
If Phoebe's gone, can we take Emma home?
如果菲比走了，我們可以 帶艾□回家嗎？
That's a good idea. Our babysitter just pounded another chardonnay.
好主意，我們的保姆 才又點了一杯白酒
- Bye, you guys. - Bye.
-再見 -再見
See you. Well, I guess it's just us.
再見，我想就只剩下我們了
So, I'm probably still ovulating. Do you want to give it another try?
我或許還在排卵 你還想再試試看嗎？
All right.
好的
So, you've never had sex with a Kennedy, have you?
你從沒有跟甘尼迪家的人上過床嗎？
Actually, Richard was a Kennedy on his mother's side.
事實上，李察他媽媽那邊 是甘尼迪家族的人
Why did you break up with that guy?
那你為什麼要跟他分手呢？
- You're gonna go do it? - We don't have much time.
-你們不會就這樣跑去做了吧？ -我們時間不多了
Once the egg descends into the fallopian tube..
一但卵子落到輸卵管…
Oh, wait, oh, get out of here!
喔，等等… 滾吧！
I sincerely hope the rest of your party is returning.
我誠摯地希望你的朋友會回來
No, just me. All alone.
不，只剩下我一個人
Dinner for six for one.
六人份晚餐全給我一個人
Well, you boys are about to see something really special.
很好，你們將會目睹到 一個非常特別的表演
- How was everything? - Excellent.
-一切都還好嗎？ -棒極了
The shrew, in particular, was exquisite.
特別是鼠肉，真是美味
I hope you've got some room left.
我希望你還有胃口
Joey. Joey.
喬伊，喬伊
This is the best birthday ever!
這是最棒的生日了！